A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants, Accession 2015:115 FA1321
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grants, 1979-2007; 1
  - Council for Excellence in Government - Strategic Plan - 09701611, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    Sections include: Introduction - Vision and Context, Gathering Speed, 18 Month Agenda, Council Partnership/Innovations Team Roles, Regional Partnerships, TV Study, Budget Tables, Overall Council Funding, Diversity Profile, About the Council, Proposed Agenda 1999-2000, Progress - Innovations and Partnership, Council Partnership/Innovations Team Roles, Projected Budget Tables, Diversity Profile, Martin and Glantz, Innovations/Partnership Programs and Publications
  - Council for Excellence in Government - Proposal to the Ford Foundation: Innovations in American Government Award Program and Partnership for Trust in Government - 09701611, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    Sections include: Proposed Agenda 1999-2000, Progress - Innovations and Partnership, Council Partnership/Innovations Team Roles, Projected Budget Tables, Diversity Profile, Martin and Glantz, Innovations/Partnership Programs and Publications, About the Council
  - Council for Excellence in Government - Press Clips: 1998-1999, Key Events and Initiatives of the Partnership for Trust in Government - 09701611 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    Sections include: Images of Government in TV Entertainment, Good Housekeeping, Girl Scouts of the USA, National Council of Churches, The Conference Board, E-News, Launch Opinion - Editorials, Why Americans Should Trust Government
  - Council for Excellence in Government - Press Clippings - 09701611, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Casa Via Magia - 09900720, 2000-2003 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    Contains: Mercado Cultural Latino Americano and Latin American Cultural Market Final Report
  - Final Report Cultural Market Latin America, 2002; 2015:115:054 (Box 45, Folder 327)
  - Imbali Visual Literacy Project - Prints - 10052059, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 74-75)
  - International Food Policy Research Institute - Agricultural R&D Policy in the Developing World, Philip G. Pardley, Julian M. Alston and Roley R. Piggott - 09900258, 2003 June 30 (Box 11, Folder 76-78)
    Asset Based Community Development (ABCD)/Community Resource Development (CRD)
  - Small Enterprise Education and Promotion (SEEP) Network Financial Statements and Reports of Independent Certified Public Accountants - 09701649, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    Assets/Economic Development
  - Center for Social and Economic Research (CASE) - Scientific Foundation - Report of the Board on the Foundation's Activities in 1998 - 10001699, 1999; Digital media in folder - 3 1/2-inch floppy disk - Grant 1000-1699 - Narrative Report, 2003 October 29 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Office of the Vice President (OVP)
    - 3½-inch floppy - Grant 1000-1699 - Narrative Report, 2003 October 29; 3 1/2-inch floppy disk (Box 11, Item 2015:115:018)
  - University of Texas at Austin - Beyond the Digital Access Divide, Michael Oden, Ph.D. - 10251194, 2004 March (Box 11, Folder 81)
    Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC)/Media, Arts and Culture (MAC)
  - Indiana University Center for Urban Policy and The Environment - Charitable Choice Research Project Meeting of Advisory Panels, Indianapolis - 10001682, 2001 January 19-20 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Indiana University Center for Urban Policy and The Environment - Faith-Based Social Service Provision Under Charitable Choice: A Study of Implementation in Three States, IUPUI - 10001682, 2002 October 2-3 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Population Displacement in the Sudan: Patterns, Responses, Coping Strategies, Gamal M. Hamid - 09350849, 1996 April; Digital media in folder - 3 1/2-inch floppy - Manuscript - Population Displacement in the Sudan: Patterns, Responses, Coping Strategies, Gamal M. Hadid, 1996 April (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - 3½-inch floppy - Manuscript - Population Displacement in the Sudan: Patterns, Responses, Coping Strategies, Gamal M. Hadid, 1996 April; 3 1/2-inch floppy disk (Box 12, Item 2015:115:019)
  - SITE Santa Fe - 10000830, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    Includes Education and Public Programs flyer from 2001, slides, and investment policy
    - SITE Santa Fe - Photos, undated (Box 12, Item 2015:115:020)
      Top: Artist in Residence at Warehouse 21 (teen center); Right: Young Curators at first opening at SF Community College; Top: Artist in Residence children from the Children's Museum
    - SITE Santa Fe Installation View and Exhibitions - slides, 1994-2002 (Box 12, Item 2015:115:021)
  - Oxfam America - Didier Jacobs - Reports - 10001450, 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC)
    Includes Wealth Inequality in the North: Recent Trends in Historical Perspective; The Impact of Financial Crises on Income Inequality; The Potential and Limitations of Foreign Direct Investment for Development; Financing Development with Special Drawing Rights; What Does It Mean to be Global Citizen? A Conceptual Review; Models of Global Citizenship; Democratizing Global Economic Governance; International Trade and Income Inequality Within and Between Nations: A Literature Review of Theory and Evidence
  - Fordham University/New York City Superintendents' Network - Implementing the Principal Performance Review - 09700345, 2000 March 6 (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Fordham University/New York City Superintendents' Network - Standards: Making Them Happen - 09700345, 1999 March 22 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - Obafemi Awolowo University - Ife Outreach Project - 10050537, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 89)
  - Mexican Center for Philanthropy - Correspondence and Financial Statements 2004 and 2005 - 10001694, 2004-2006 (Box 13, Folder 90)
  - National Academy of Education - Committee on Teacher Education Draft: Preparing Teachers for a Changing World - 10300468, 2003 December (Box 13, Folder 91)
    Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom (KCF)/Education, Sexuality, Religion (ESR)
  - Board of Regents of the University of Texas at Austin - Latino USA - 09701095, 1998-2002 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    Includes: Appendix A: Description of Programs; Quantitative Review 1993-2000 Latino USA Programs Including Program Elements Sorted by Subject and Location and Project Rundowns 1993-2000
  - Ateneo de Davao University - Module Writers Meeting "Engendering the Curriculum of Mass Communication and Development Communication" - 09600995, 2003 January 31-February 1 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    Sponsored by the Ateneo Task Force and Mindanao Working Group on Reproductive Health, Gender and Sexuality
  - Habeas Corpus Working Group (HCWG) - 10250487, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 94)
    Note from original folder: In Storage on Reel #9132
    Includes Shadow Report - Joint Report of the Women Against Violence (NANE) Association and the Habeas Corpus Working Group (HCWG) on the realization of the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women Hungary incorporated with the critical examination of the report of the Hungarian government presented at the 2002 August session of the CEDAW Committee of the UN; A Summary Report of the Habeas Corpus Working Group on Penal Discrimination Against Gays and Bisexuals in Hungary; Background Material for an Application for Support by the Ford Foundation; Habeas Corpus estek: A Cafe Microban
  - Columbia University - National Center for Children in Poverty - 09701578, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 95)
    Includes: 1998 Program Summary and Young Children and Families in Poverty: An Agenda for Building Knowledge and Commitments in a Period of Change, A Proposal for Core Support submitted to the Ford Foundation by the National Center for Children in Poverty, Columbia School of Public Health
  - Women & Philanthropy - 10550139, 2005 October (Box 13, Folder 96)
    Narrative and financial report to cover office moving expenses
  - Columbia University - Center for the Study of Wealth and Inequality - 10001729, 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 97-100)
    Research papers
    Folder 97) Israeli Attitudes about Inter Vivos Transfers; Living Standard Potential and the Transmission of Advantage in Chile, Seymour Spilerman and Florencia Torche; A Household Wealth and Vulnerability: Results from Chile, Seymour Spilerman and Florencia Torche; Unequal But Fluid? An International Comparative Analysis Social Mobility in Chile, Florencia Torche; Educational Expansion, Privatization Reform and Growing Inequality in Chile, Florencia Torche
    Folder 98) Wealth and Intergenerational Inequality: Parental Wealth and the Socioeconomic Outcome of Adult Children, Hannah Cho; Housing Inequality in New York City: Rural and Ethnic Disparities in Homeownership and Shelter Cost Burden, Yuvel Elmelech; Race, Ethnicity, and the Gender Poverty Gap, Yuval Elmelech and Hsien-Hen Lu; Determinants of Minority-White Differentials in Child Poverty, Yuval Elmelech and Hsien-Hen Lu; Assets for the Poor: The Benefits of Spreading Asset Ownership, Thomas M. Shapiro, Edward Wolff; The Impact of Parental Wealth on Early Living Standards in Israel, Seymour Spilerman
    Folder 99) Transmitting Inequality: An Asset-Based Analysis of Racial and Ethnic Inequality and its Intergenerational Transmission, Yuval Elmelech
    Folder 100) Unequal but Fluid: Social Mobility in Chile in a Comparative Perspective, Florencia Torche
  - Niger Okan Cultural Center - 10002044, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Box 101, Box 15, Folder 102-104)
    Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, and Religion (EKR)
    Includes: Project: Cultural and Community Development in Brazil Report 2001 and Accounting Documents 1-5
  - The Nehru Memorial Museum and Library Society - The Diversity of Muslim Women's Lives in India, Maitreyi Bordia Das - 09501507, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 105)
  - American Forum - Articles and Sample Clips - 10350717, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 106)
    Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom (KCF)/Media, Arts and Culture (MAC)/Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Governance and Civil Society (GCS)
  - International Alert - Standing Forum on Ethnic Conflict - Women's Issues - 10000559, 1999-2002 (Box 16, Folder 107)
    Includes: Online Working Group on Women and Armed Conflict; Feasibility Study Mapping of Women, Peace and Security Issues Nigeria: Women Building Peace Campaign; NGO Working Group on Women, Peace, and Security; Regional and National Consultations; Women Building Peace: From the Village Council to the Negotiation Table
    - CD - War and Peace: Women's Perspectives and Experiences, 2000; CD (Box 16, Item 2015:115:022)
      Women Building Peace: The International Campaign to Promote the Role of Women in Peacebuilding
  - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum - Visual Arts - Fact Sheets and Press Releases - 10000827, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 108)
    - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum - Partnerships with Students - slides, 1999-2000 (Box 16, Item 2015:115:023)
    - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum/Japanese American National Museum photos, 1999-2000 (Box 16, Item 2015:115:024)
  - Enterprise Corporation of The Delta - Jackson Attachment - 09701512, 1998-2000 (Box 16, Folder 109)
    Asset Based Community Development (ABCD)/Economic Development (ED)
  - The Mississippi Delta Series: Incredible Potential The Clarion-Ledger, Reprinted with Permission of The Clarion-Ledger, 1999-2000; 2015:115:055 (Box 45, Folder 328)
  - Center for Resource Economics - (Attach), Washington, D.C. - Island Press - 09800773, 1995-1997 (Box 16, Folder 110)
    Asset Based Community Development (ABCD)/Community and Resource Development (CRD)
  - Fannie Lou Hamer Project - 10351022, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 111)
    The Real Color of Money Press Release and Press Material; Campaign Finance Press Material; Fannie Lou Hamer Project Conference
  - The Monterey Institute of International Studies - The United Nations Register of Conventional Arms: Origins and Evolution 1988-1994 - Volume I - 09300522 (Box 17, Folder 112)
  - The Monterey Institute of International Studies - The United Nations Register of Conventional Arms: Origins and Evolution 1988-1994 - Volume II - 09300522 (Box 17, Folder 113)
  - The Monterey Institute of International Studies - The United Nations Register of Conventional Arms: Origins and Evolution 1988-1994 - Volume III - 09300522 (Box 17, Folder 114)
  - New England Foundation for the Arts - Roundtable Reports - Preview Forum - 10200609, 2003-2005 (Box 17, Folder 115)
    Includes: "Teenagers in a Changing America" Guide for Using the Discussion Video; Practicing Facilitating a Small Group Discussion; Final Narrative Report Submitted by Roundtable, Inc. Spring 2003: Ethnicity and Race in a Changing America, National Public Engagement Initiative; Final Narrative Report, Spring 2004: Globalization: Making the Local Connection, National Public Engagement Initiative; "Globalization: Making the Local Connection" Guide for Using the Discussion Video
  - Family Care International, Inc. - (Attach), New York, New York - 09701514, 1996-2003 (Box 17, Folder 116)
    Asset Based Community Development (ABCD)/Human Development and Reproductive Health (HDRH)
    Fact sheets, Notes, Resource Guide on the Prevention and Management of Unsafe Abortion: Proposal Summary; Family Care International, Inc. - Finanancial Statements and Supplementary Information 1997 and 1996
  - Rush Philanthropic Arts Foundation - Correspondence and Press Materials - 10150514, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - Milan Šimečka Foundation - Attachment File - 09850863, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 118)
    Includes: Repertoires of connection in post-communist protest cultures: an East Central European comparative survey, Szabo, Mate; Assessing the implications of political and economic reform in the post-socialist era: the case of Czech and Slovak women; Purpose and Mission
  - Pangea World Theater - Bridges - Germinations - 10350908, 2004 February (Box 18, Folder 119)
  - Johns Hopkins University - 09801559, 2002-2004 (Box 18, Folder 120)
    Includes: Attachment B Phase IIB Local Advisory Committees; Attachment C - Global Civil Society Volume II; Attachment D - Sample Press Coverage; Chapter 2 Measuring Civil Society: The Johns Hopkins Global Civil Society Index; Handbook on Nonprofit Institutions in the System of National Accounts Information Packet, Center for Civil Society Studies; Handbook on Nonprofit Institutions in the System of National Accounts, United Nations Statistics Division
  - Women Advocates Research & Documentation Center (WARDC) - Nigeria - 10150225, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 121)
    - Zavia (sp?) Conference on Women and Constitutionalism - photos, undated (Box 18, Item 2015:115:025)
    - 3 Day Seminar/Workshop on Women and Constitutionalism - Formulating Strategies for Inclusion of Women in the Constitution Making Process in Nigeria, Lagos - photos, 2001 July 17-19 (Box 18, Item 2015:115:026)
    - WARDC - Inclusion of Women in the Constitution Making Process Meeting/Workshop - photos, 2001 (Box 18, Item 2015:115:027)
    - Women Advocates Research and Documentation Center (WARDC) - photos, 2002 (Box 18, Item 2015:115:028)
  - Harvard University - Roy and Lila Ash Institute for Democratic Governance and Innovation - 10100583, 2000-2006 (Box 18, Folder 122)
    Proposal for a Grant to Endow - The Innovations in American Government Program and a New Institute for Government Innovation at John F. Kennedy School of Government; Plan Document; Work Plan; Correspondence; Annual Repot 2006; Background Note; Memos; Grant Notification Letter
  - Harvard University - Ash Institute Financials - 10100583, 2001-2007 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - National Council for Community Development, Inc. - Attachment Folder, New York, New York - 09901111, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 124)
    The American Dream and the Creation of a New Shareholder Society
  - United Nations University - World Trade Organization Report Manuscript - 10150620, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 125)
  - The Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda - Glimpses of the Campus Diversity Initiative - 09701181, 1997-2000 (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Council on Foundations - Correspondence, Notes, and Approved Budget - 10001223, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 127)
  - Yunnan University/Faculty of Anthropology - Project to Preserve and Improve Villages of Ethnic Minority Groups in Yunnan, China - 10001560, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 128)
    A Report on the First-Phase Achievements in the Project for the Construction of Ethnic and Ecological Villages in Yunnan, China, The Project Team for the Construction of Ethnic Cultural and Ecological Villages in Yunnan, China with Grant Awarded by the Ford Foundation, Beijing
  - Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania - Carnegie Learning, Inc. - Pump Algebra I - 09701864, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 129)
    OVS/Peace and Social Justice (PSJ)/Office of Vice President (OVP)/Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)
  - St. Louis Symphony - slides and photos - 10000815, 2000-2001; 2015:115:029 (Box 19, Item 2015:115:029)
  - Prince Music Theater - color slides, 1994 (Box 19, Item 2015:115:030)
  - Philippine Educational Theatre Association - Komedi Club - Libby Manaoag - Dreamweavers - Appendices - Photo Narrative - 10000462, 2000 July-2001 June (Box 19, Item 2015:115:031)
    Report with pictures taped to pages
  - Harvard University - Politics - Roberto Mangabeira Unger - Introduction: The Context of Social Theory at the Close of the Twentieth Century - 07900395, 1979-1982 (Box 19, Folder 130)
    Education and Research (ER)
  - Harvard University - Politics - Roberto Mangabeira Unger - Part I: False Necessity - 07900395, 1979-1982 (Box 20, Folder 131)
  - Harvard University - Politics - Roberto Mangabeira Unger - Part II: Worldly Success - 07900395, 1979-1982 (Box 20, Folder 132-133)
  - Harvard University - Politics - Roberto Mangabeira Unger - Part III: Surprising Passion - 07900395, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 134-136)
  - Harvard University - Politics - Roberto Mangabeira Unger - Appendix - 07900395, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 137)
    ER (Education and Research)
  - Opera Theatre of St. Louis - Financial Statements - 10000818, 2004 September 30 (Box 21, Folder 138)
    Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC)/Media Arts and Culture (MAC)
    National Civic League (NCL)
    - Opera Theatre of St. Louis - slides, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Item 2015:115:032)
      Slide Captions: The Tale of Orphans, The Merchant and the Pauper, and Joshua's Boots
  - Americans for the Arts - 10001633, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 139)
    Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Media Arts and Culture (MAC)
    Includes: Flint Youth Theatre - My Soul to Take; Most Requested Arts Statistics From National Arts Information Clearinghouse; National Arts and Humanities Month October 2000; Animating Democracy Initiative, Chicago; Arts Advocacy Day: The National Arts Action Summit, March 20, 2001 - Congressional Arts Handbook Facts and Figures at Your Fingertips; National Arts Education Public Action Campaign Survey, May 2001
  - Steppenwolf Theater Company - slides - 10000826, 1988-2000 (Box 21, Item 2015:115:033)
    Includes slides of Gary Sinise and Terry Kinney in The Grapes of Wrath and K. Todd Freeman and John Mahoney in the Song of Jacob Zulu
  - International Action Network on Small Arms (IANSA) - 10100825, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 140)
    Includes: Annex 1: Comments from IANSA participants in August 2002 in a survey of "What difference has the existence of IANSA made to them in their work?"; Annex 2: Grants for Regional, Sub-Regional and Thematic Small Arms Activities; Annex 3: Brief Report on IANSA "Funds for Networking" February/March 2002; Annex 12: Draft Agenda for IANSA Facilitation Committee; IANSA Contact List December 2002; Draft - Small Arms and Light Weapons: A Resource Manual: International Alert and Saferworld, Jim Coe and Oliver Sprague; Annex 5: Press Clippings, March 2002-2003
  - Institute of International Education, Inc. - 09600148, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 141)
    US International Affairs (USIA)/Office of the Vice President (OVP)
    Recommendation for Grant/FAP Action and Financial Statements
    - "Inroads Africa" - Breakfast at Ford Foundation, Reception at the Museum for African Art, Conference at the Hotel St. Moritz, Conference at NYU - Contact Prints, 1996 June 5-8 (Box 22, Item 2015:115:046)
  - Sanchetana Community Health and Research Centre - 10050133, 2001-2003 (Box 22, Folder 142-143)
    Includes: Footprints in the Sands of Time - Annual Report 2002-2003 and Documentation of grounds gained by us in Instating Women's Rights and Social Justice 1998-2002 Submitted to the Ford Foundation, New Delhi by The Women's Programme, Sanchetana, Ahmedabad, Gujarat; Breaking New Grounds...Annual Report 2001-2002 The Women's Programme, Sanchetana, Submitted to the Ford Foundation, New Delhi
  - Consumers Union of the United States - 10101037, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 144)
    Assets/Economic Development (ED)
    Manufactured Housing Testing Project (January 1, 2002 - December 31, 2002): An Audit of Manufactured Housing Retailers' Sales Practices toward African-American and Hispanic Homebuyers in South Central, Central, and North Central Texas, Prepared for the Consumers' Union Southwest Regional Office by the Austin Tenants' Council Fair Housing Program
  - National Forum for Public Policy and Development (NAFOPPODE) - 10100267, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 145)
    Making the Constitution a Living Instrument for the Rule of Law and Good Governance, Republic of Liberia
  - Rainforest Alliance - Annual Progress Report - 10100674, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 146)
  - California Tomorrow - 10100835, 2003 March (Box 23, Folder 147)
    Correspondence regarding "Biingual and Bicultural Children, Families, Schools, and Communities Project"
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem - The Palestinians in the Twentieth Century: An Inside View - Summary of Activities - 09900868, 1999 September-2000 March (Box 23, Folder 148)
  - Youth Build USA, Inc. - Press Highlights - 10400174, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 149)
    Assets/Community Resource Development (CRD)
  - Local Initiative Support Training and Education Network (LISTEN) - 10001337, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 150)
    Assets/HD
    Includes: Are you LISTENing to Urban Youth: A Need for LISTEN, Inc.; Ella J. Baker Leadership and Technology Public Charter School (EJB)
  - National Association of Development Organizations (NADO) - Deal Structuring Manual, Mark Barbash - 09700641, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 151)
    A Step-by-Step Guidebook to Financing Business Projects for Economic Development Professionals
  - National Association of Development Organizations (NADO) - Economic Development Finance Service (EDFS) - Revolving Loan Fund Organization & Administration - 09700641, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 152)
  - National Association of Development Organizations (NADO) - Economic Development Finance Service (EDFS) - Loan Fund Capitalization Strategies - 09700641, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 153)
  - National Association of Development Organizations (NADO) - Economic Development Finance Service (EDFS) - Financial Statements and Credit Analysis for Revolving Loan Funds - 09700641, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 154)
  - The International Ecotourism Society (TIES) - 10101032, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 155)
    Includes: Bar Harbor Declaration on Ecotourism in the US; The Development of Results-Oriented Indicators For Tourism Accommodations Final Report, Bob Toth; Marketing Sustainable Tourism Certification, Martha Honey and Amos Bien; Center on Ecotourism and Sustainable Development (CESD); Fact Sheet; Trade Issues in Sustainable Tourism Certification: An Examination of the Constraints Imposed by International Trade Rules and Organizations (NAFTA, WTO, etc.) Barriers to Trade; Digital Traveler - Asia Pacific
  - National Asian Pacific American Legal Consortium - Exhibit 1-20 - 09801632, 2001-2003 (Box 23, Folder 156)